Brendan Greene

Turnings Straffan Co.Kildare

T +353.1.627.8948 M +353.86.391.8623

brendanjgreene@gmail.com github.com/brendanjgreene

Profile

The skills I have acquired as a graduate of the Code Institute and Edinburgh Napier University; combined with my experience working in the Community Psychology settings gives me a unique set of qualifications and skills. For example, my education as a Community Psychologist gives me insight into how UI design needs to be simple for the everyday user.

Skills

HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Python including Django and Flask Frameworks, jQuery, JavaScript, GitHub, AngularJS, mySQL and SQLite, d3.js and dc.js. Interpersonal skills gained from working with a wide range people of varying abilities and backgrounds both in the United States and Ireland.

Experience

Social Care Worker, Kare; Newbridge, Kildare – 2003-2016

Used computer skills to improve Rostering and Medication administration procedures and forms while simultaneously working on a team of Care Workers caring for people with intellectual disabilities and challenging behaviour.

Supportive Employment Specialist, Hospitaller Order of St. John of God; Bluebell, Dublin 12 – 2002-2003

Supported individuals with Intellectual disabilities to obtain and succeed at Jobs in their Community.

Quality Assurance Manager II, AHRC-MSC Unit; New York, NY, USA – 2001-2002 Supervise a Team of Service-Coordinators as they implemented Individualised Service Plans and insured that they were compliant with the NYS-Medicaid Waiver Program.

Intensive Behaviourist-Independent Living Skills Trainer, Altamount TBI Program; Menands, NY, USA – 1998-200

Independent Living Skills Training and Intensive Behaviour Counselling for people with Acquired Brain Injury and Substance Abuse Issues.

Community Resource Trainer, AHRC-TBI Services; New York, NY, USA – 1994-1998 Trained people with Acquired Brain Injury to access the Community.

Education

The Code Institute Dublin & Edinburgh Napier University – Full Stack Diploma in Software Development, 2017

Sage Graduate School; Albany, NY – MA; Community Psychology, 2000 State University of New York; Stony Brook, NY – BA; Psychology and Studio Art, 1993

Interests
References

My local football club; Coaching and web development. Marathon running. Available upon request.